Jessa M. Cahilig

101 M.L. Quezon Street Parang, Marikina City, Philippines, 1809 (+63) 9176202391

iam@jessacahilig.com

Summary

Software Engineer with more than nine years experience in Android and Java development. Experience in creating cross-platform apps using React and cordova framework as well as web applications using Javascript. Areas of strength include implementation of analytics, UX tests, and monetization efforts in app. An innovative individual and team- player with proven knowledge with variety of technical tools and methodologies in software development.

Employment History

INNOVATION LOVE

2019- present

A start-up company. Developing human-centered innovations.

Full Stack Software Engineer

Create and maintain Onepropertee, a real-estate online platform for both buyers, brokers and developers using Javascript framework.

Selected Key Accomplishments:

- One of the first team members to join the team in creating the web and mobile apps.
- Key person in both android and iOS apps development.
- Adapt fast from native to cross-platform mobile development.
- Deployed the OnePropertee apps in playstore and appstore respectively.

CAROUSELL PHILIPPINES (OLX PHILIPPINES)

2015-2019

Philippines' No. 1 Buy and Sell Website

Lead Software Engineer for Mobile Apps

2017-2019

Manage other mobile developers' performance and maintenance of OLX's android app while on transition with the new Carousell platform. Attends weekly planning and assists concerns of newly onboarded members to the team.

Selected Key Accomplishments:

- Mentored newly outsourced developers for both android and ios platforms keeping a frictionless onboarding procedure.
- Migration to new Carousell platform.

• Contribute to product planning as well as project management for the team's scrum and sprint planning.

Android Software Engineer

2015-2017

Full responsibility in development and maintenance of OLX's android app. Attends weekly sprint planning and daily stand-ups to make sure that all tasks are delivered in time and effectively.

Selected Key Accomplishments:

- Developed an effective chat feature that improved buyer and seller contacts in android.
- Implemented monetization efforts to align web and app features as well as additional sources of revenue such as Google and Facebook ads.
- Contributed in enhancing CI/CD in android by communicating with test engineers.

IBM PHILIPPINES 2014- 2015

Global leader in delivering IT solutions and innovation

Application Developer - Core Java

Comply with client-based development requirements in existing system using Java language. Participate in stand up and scrum meetings with partner companies from other countries.

Selected Key Accomplishments:

• Assigned in a global military investment and insurance client with strict data security and policy among billable/ on-boarded developers.

COMNET MANAGEMENT CORP.

2013-2014

Provider of online betting games and consulting services

Software Engineer/ System Analyst

Design, development and maintenance of Lottocell platform, an online betting app for PCSO's (Philippines Charity Sweepstakes Office) Bingo Milyonaryo game. Acts as technical representative in internal and external company meetings.

Selected Key Accomplishments:

- Production release of Lottocell app inline with the launch of PCSO's Bingo Milyonaryo game nationwide, the game was aired for 1 year via PTV 4 (government owned TV channel).
- Refactored the Lottocell app multiple times to cater legal/ government requirements and changes in thermal printer suppliers.

IDEAWURX INC. 2011-2013

Start up company providing software solutions and telecommunication services

Software Engineer

Create various in-house and client-based applications. Attends daily stand up and project planning.

Selected Key Accomplishments:

- Developed numerous android projects such as MyCab (SMS based taxi reservation, Lottocell (betting game) and Virtual Buddy (VOIP).
- Enabled the Lottocell app to print hard copy receipts via Bluetooth and OTG USB cable.
- Delivered a fully working J2ME app in just one week of development.

Education

2007 to 2011 Manuel S. Enverga University Foundation

BS Information Technology Cum Laude

Selected Trainings

- Google Developer Group DevFest 2017, Philippines
- UXPH 2017, Philippines
- OLX Panamera Monetization Workshop 2017, India